Thank you.
I love you.
This is a story of Boy Meets Girl.
The boy, Tom Hanson of Margate, New Jersey,
grew up believing that he'd never truly be happy
until the day he met the one.
This belief stemmed from early exposure to sad British pop music
and a total misreading of the movie The Graduate.
The girl, Summer Finn of Shinnecock, Michigan, did not share this belief.
Since the disintegration of her parents' marriage, she'd only loved two things.
The first was her long, dark hair.
The second was how easily she could cut it off and feel nothing.
Tom meets Summer on January 8th.
He knows almost immediately she's who he's been searching for.
This is a story of boy meets girl.
But you should know up front, this is not a love story.
They made a statue of us
And they put it on a mountaintop
And the tourists come and stare at us
Blow bubbles with their gum
Take photographs of fun
Have fun
They'll name a city after us
And later say it's all our fault
Then they'll give us a talking to
Cause they've got years of experience
Living in a den of thieves
Rummaging for answers in the pages
I'm living in a den of thieves
And it's contagious
I'm sorry.
We knew who else to call.
It's Amanda Heller all over again.
He did the right thing.
Now where is he?
Thomas?
Rachel.
What are you doing here?
I'm here to help you.
Help me, huh?
First, put down the plate.
Drink this.
What is that? Vodka.
Um, does Mom know that you're here?
Because it's probably past 10.
Don't worry about it.
Just start from the beginning and tell us what happened.
Things were going so well.
Then what?
I think we should stop seeing each other.
Just like that?
Just like that.
Did you say why?
I mean, this thing.
What are we doing?
I mean, is this normal?
Normal?
I don't know.
I don't care.
I'm happy.
Aren't you happy?
You're happy?
You're not.
All we do is argue.
That is bullshit.
Then maybe she was just in a bad mood.
Yeah, maybe like a hormonal thing.
PMS?
What do you know about PMS?
More than you, Tom.
Then what happened?
This can't come as a total surprise to you.
I mean, we've been like Sid and Nancy for months now.
Summer, Sid stabbed Nancy.
Seven times at the kitchen.
I mean, we have some disagreements,
but I hardly think I'm Sid Vicious.
No, I'm Sid.
Oh, so I'm Nancy.
Let's just eat and we'll talk about it later.
Mmm, that is good.
I'm really glad we did this.
I love these pancakes.
What?
Tom, don't go.
You're still my best friend.
Jesus.
You've broken up with girls before?
Yes.
And girls have broken up with you before?
This is different.
Why?
Because it's summer.
So you'll meet somebody new.
Point is, you're the best guy I know.
You'll get over her.
I think it's kind of like how they say,
there's plenty of other fish in the sea.
No.
They say that.
Well, they're lying.
I don't want to get over her.
I want to get her back.
Maybe playing it safe is the wrong approach.
The nuclear family is dead,
and we need a new holiday that recognizes that.
May 21st.
Other Mother's Day.
Thank you.
I'd say we've got some potential here.
What do you think, Hanson?
Could you write up some prototypes for these?
Mr. Vance, there's a telephone call for you on line three.
Oh, thank you.
Everyone, this is Summer, my new assistant.
Summer just moved here from...
Michigan.
Right, Michigan, right.
Uh, Summer, everyone? Everyone?
Summer. Excuse me, I have to take this.
It's nice to meet you all.
There's only two kinds of people in the world.
There's women and there's men.
Summer Finn was a woman.
Height, average.
Weight, average.
Shoe size, slightly above average.
For all intents and purposes, Summer Finn, just another girl.
Except she wasn't.
To wit, in 1998, Summer quoted a song by the Scottish band Belle and Sebastian in her high school yearbook,
Color My Life with the Chaos of Trouble.
This spike in Michigan sales of their album, The Boy with the Arab Strap, continues to puzzle industry analysts.
Summer's employment at the Daily Freeze during her sophomore year coincided with an inexplicable 212% increase in revenue.
Every apartment Summer rented was offered at an average rate of 9.2% below market value.
And her round-trip commute to work averaged 18.4 double-takes per day.
It was a rare quality, this Summer effect.
Rare and yet something every post-adolescent male has encountered at least once in their lives.
For Tom Hanson to find it now in a city of 400,000 offices, 91,000 commercial buildings, and 3.8 million people,
well, that could only be explained by one thing.
Fate.
Dude, I hear she's a bitch.
Really?
Yeah, Patel tried to talk to her in the copy room.
She's totally not having it.
Maybe she was just in a hurry.
And maybe she's an uppity
better than everyone's super skank.
Damn.
I know. She's pretty hot.
That sucks. Why is it pretty girls think
they can treat people like crap and get away with it?
Centuries of reinforcement.
You know what? Screw her. I don't care.
She wants to be that way, fine.
I love the Smiths.
Sorry?
I said I love the Smiths.
You've... you've got taste in music.
You like the Smiths?
Yeah.
To die by your side is such a heavenly way to die.
I love them.
Holy shit.
There you go.
Nosepiece.
Drinks?
All right, thanks.
All right.
Yeah.
Summer, right?
Smith's fan.
Yeah.
Tom.
Want some, uh...
Uh, it's not champagne.
I don't know what it is.
Sure.
So, how's it going?
Pretty good.
You just moved here, right?
Mm-hmm.
When?
Saturday.
Oh, wow.
And what brought you?
Boredom, mostly.
Wanted to try something new and exciting.
Mm. Clearly you've come to the right place.
So have you worked here long?
About three or four years.
Wow.
You...
always wanted to write greeting cards?
No, I don't even want to do it now.
Well, you should do something else then.
Yeah, I studied to be an architect, actually.
You did? That's cool.
What happened there?
It didn't work out.
I needed a job, and here we are.
You any good?
Well, um, I wrote this one.
Today, you're a man.
Mazel tov on your bar mitzvah.
It's a big seller.
I meant as an architect.
Yeah.
I doubt it.
Well, you're a perfectly adequate greeting card writer.
Thank you.
That was actually my nickname in college.
They called me Perfectly Adequate Hanson.
You used to call me Anal Girl.
I was very neat and organized.
Well, I should get back, so...
All right. See you later.
I'm sorry.
I don't know, man.
I think it's official.
I'm in love with Summer.
I love her smile.
I love her hair.
I love her knees.
I love this heart-shaped birthmark she has on her neck.
I love the way she sometimes licks her lips before she talks.
I love the sound of her laugh.
I love the way she looks when she's sleeping.
I love how I hear this song every time I think of her.
I love how she makes me feel.
Like...
Like anything's possible.
Like, I don't know, like...
Like life is worth it.
This is not good.
She likes Magritte and Hopper.
And we talked about Banana Fish for like 20 minutes.
We were so compatible, it was insane.
She's, I don't know, she's not like I thought at all.
She's amazing.
Oh, boy.
What?
Just because some cute girl likes the same bizarro crap you do,
that doesn't make her your soulmate, Dom.
What do you mean?
It's off
What?
I mean, Summer
Was it ever on?
No, but it could have been in a world where good things happen to me
Yeah, well, that's not really where we live
No
So what happened?
You ready?
Yeah
So there we are
Nine more floors to write, just me and her
Hey, Summer
Hi
How's your weekend?
It was good.
Can you believe that shit?
I'm sorry, what shit?
I think I missed something.
She said it was good. Emphasis on the good.
She basically said she spent the weekend having sex with some guy she met at the gym.
Skank. Whatever. I'm over it.
What the hell is wrong with you?
She's not interested in me. There's really nothing I can do about that.
Just because she said it was good. And some other things.
Like, did she say, uh, hey instead of hi?
I mean, because you know that means that she's a lesbian, right?
I gave her plenty of chances.
I'm going to the supply room. Do you guys need anything?
I think you know what I need.
I'll tell her.
Okay, sure, no problem.
See the look I've had can make a good man turn bad.
So please, please, please let me, let me, let me,
let me get what I want.
Whatever man, it's fine.
I don't need this crap really.
I'm comfortable, unhassled.
People don't realize this, but loneliness...
It's underrated.
You could just ask her out.
Don't be stupid.
This Friday, all-you-can-karaoke at the mill.
No.
Come on.
They're not gonna let you back in there after last time.
Eh, it wasn't that bad.
That's not that bad.
Dude, you threw up on the stage, you tried to fight the bartender, you threatened to
burn the place down.
But I didn't burn the place down.
I'm not going back there.
Look, it's not like that, okay?
It's a work thing.
The whole office is going.
I can't go even if I wanted to.
You're not listening to me.
What?
The whole office is going.
Just like every cowboy
He's a sad, sad song
Every rose has its
Hi.
They said you weren't coming.
You asked if I was coming.
God damn, that song is brilliant.
What song is it?
That's me.
You up?
Okay, I'm new, so no making fun of me.
Thanks, kid.
Aw, thanks.
Cheers.
I got some troubles, but they won't last
I'm gonna lay right down here in the grass
And pretty soon all my troubles will pass
Cause I'm a shoo-shoo-shoo
A shoo-shoo-shoo
A shoo-shoo-shoo-shoo-shoo-shoo
Sugar town
Like, that's what it is.
Uh, yes.
Hello.
I didn't, uh, I didn't know you were gonna join us.
I would have gotten you, you know, a drink.
I'm good.
You good?
You were great.
Great at singing.
Thank you.
I wanted to sing Born to Run, but they didn't have it.
I love Born to Run.
Me too.
Tom's from New Jersey.
Really?
Yeah, I grew up there.
I lived there until I was 12.
I named my cat after Springsteen.
Okay.
What was his name?
Bruce.
That makes sense.
So you have a boyfriend?
No.
Why not?
Because I don't want one.
Come on. I don't believe that.
You don't believe that a woman could enjoy being free and independent?
Are you a lesbian?
No, I'm not a lesbian.
I just don't feel comfortable being anyone's girlfriend.
I don't actually feel comfortable being anyone's anything, you know?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Really?
Nope.
Okay. Let me break it down for you.
Break it down.
Okay. I like being on my own.
Relationships are messy and people's feelings get hurt.
Who needs it? We're young.
We live in one of the most beautiful cities in the world.
Might as well have fun while we can
and save the serious stuff for later.
Holy shit, you're a dude. She's a dude.
Okay, but wait, wait.
What happens if you fall in love?
What?
You don't believe that, do you?
It's love. It's not Santa Claus.
What does that word even mean?
I've been in relationships and I don't think I've ever seen it.
Well, maybe that's...
And most marriages end in divorce these days.
Like my parents'.
Okay, mine too, but...
Me thinks the lady doth protest too much.
The lady dothn't.
There's no such thing as love, it's fantasy.
Well, I think you're wrong.
Okay, well...
What is it that I'm missing, then?
I think you know when you feel it
I guess we can just agree to disagree
Yeah
Okay
Who's singing next?
I nominate young Berta here
I'm not nearly drunk enough to
Bartender
Never wait, baby, never wait so long.
So long, so long.
Never wait so long.
Here comes your man.
You're good.
Is it da, da, da, na, na, na, na?
No?
No, it's not it.
What is that then?
I don't know.
That, that, that's something.
I know.
I used to watch it every week.
Oh, yeah.
It's the best show on TV.
I know.
Knight Rider?
Come on.
And the theme song is really good.
So good.
This is going to bother me for a week.
Me too.
And I'm proud to be in America
Where at least I know I'm free
And I'm right to live the day to day
You were amazing.
I know, right?
You're amazing.
I know.
This was so much fun.
You guys are so much better.
Wait, wait, hey.
What's up?
Not you. You.
He likes you.
Okay, good night, McKenzie.
He likes you. Why don't you just tell her, Tom?
Yeah.
Sorry.
Yeah, we've seen that piece.
Happens every time we come here.
He, uh, I don't know, something about that guy and singing.
Is that true?
Yeah, yeah, he drinks and he sings
and just loses his shit.
No, uh, not McKenzie.
Um, the other thing?
What thing?
Do you like me?
Yeah.
Yeah, of course I like you.
As friends?
Right, as friends.
Just as friends?
Yeah. I mean, I...
I don't know, I hadn't really thought about it.
Yes. Why?
No reason. I just...
I think you're interesting, and I'd like for us to be friends.
Is that all right?
Yeah, it's...
Yeah, you and me, we should be friends.
Mm. Okay. Good.
Well, from that point, it's me.
Okay.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Hey.
Hi.
So that was fun.
I'm sorry.
You son of a bitch.
The same girl you've been obsessing over for weeks now?
Not been obsessing.
The girl you said was way out of your league
that you'd never have a chance with in a million years.
That girl.
Paul, seriously.
Did you bang her?
No.
What, hum job?
Hand job?
Man, no.
No jobs.
I'm still unemployed.
We kissed.
Level with me, man.
Come on.
He's your best friend, huh?
Your best friend who tolerated you whining about this girl for weeks on end.
You were essentially stalking her.
Oh!
Hi.
Hey.
I'm Summer.
Hmm.
Summer.
I'm Paul.
Hi, Paul.
Nice to meet you.
Well, I gotta go.
I gotta do some, you know...
Yeah, man.
Um, just pretend I was never here.
Oh, wait, Tom, Tom, Tom, Tom.
Um, if any jobs come up...
Thanks, Paul. See ya.
He's, uh...
No. Old friend.
If you heard any of, um...
Heard what?
Nothing. You want to go?
Yeah, I'm stalking. I mean, I'm starving.
Uh-huh.
Our sink is broken.
Man, all of our sinks are broken.
What are we looking for again?
Uh, trivets?
How about a flug?
No, I don't think so.
No?
You don't want a flug?
Home, sweet home.
Our place really is.
Lovely, isn't it?
Yes.
Ooh, idols on.
TV's not working.
Oh.
Well, I'm famished.
Let's eat.
Mm.
Smells delicious.
Oh, honey, that's because it is delicious.
I made it myself.
Bald eagle.
Your favorite.
Mm-hmm.
The sink's broken.
Well, that's okay, because...
I'm not a big fan of that.
That's why we bought a home with two kitchens.
You're so smart.
I'll wait for you in the bedroom.
Darling, I don't know how to tell you this, but...
there's a Chinese family in our bathroom.
There's a Chinese family in our bathroom.
This is fun.
You're fun.
Thanks.
Hey, um, I just want to tell you that, um,
I'm not really looking for anything serious.
Is that okay?
Yeah.
Because some people kind of freak out when they hear that.
Yeah, me.
You sure?
Yeah, like, casual.
I take it slow.
No pressure.
I'm sorry.
Can you wait one second?
Okay, settle.
She's just a girl.
Just a girl.
She wants to keep it casual.
Which is why she's in my bed right now.
But that's casual, and that's what casual people do.
It's fine. It's great.
Hi.
We'll be right back.
You make my dreams come true
You, you, you, you, you
Well, well, well, you
Oh, yeah
You make my dreams come true
You, you, you, you
Oh, yeah
You
On a night when I'm bed
I think of a screamer
When I'm messing with a dreamer
I got the love that is a face
Twist and shout my way out
And wrap yourself around me
Cause I ain't the way you found me
And I'll never be the same
Oh yeah, well, cause you
You make my dreams come true
You, you, you
Well, well, well, you
You make my dreams come true
Listen to this
I'm down on my daydream
Oh, that sleepwalk should be over by now
I know
Oh, you
Yeah, yeah
I'm gonna get Alfredo's number.
Okay.
And I'll bring it to you.
Okay?
So did you get her back yet or what?
Working on it.
Maybe you should write a book.
All right.
Well, you know, Henry Miller said the best way to get over a woman
is to turn her into literature.
That guy had a lot more sex than me.
Oh! Zip, zip.
So great to hear from you.
I can't this week, but maybe next.
I hope this means you're ready to be friends.
Yeah, that's it.
That is it.
Your girl is losing it.
Let me just be serious.
I am being totally serious.
Oh, you're joking around.
No, I am not joking around.
Octopus's Garden.
Yes, Octopus's Garden's the best Beatles song ever recorded.
Why don't you just say piggies?
Come on, I love Ringo Starr.
Nobody loves Ringo Starr.
That's what I love about him.
Ooh, this looks good.
Gets really good reviews.
You know what? That looks pretty doable.
Why are you asking me?
Is this busy right?
Wait a minute.
What?
Three, two, one.
Yeah, the street level isn't so exciting,
but like, if you look up.
Fine arts building.
Guys are designing this Walker and Eisner.
Two of my favorites.
Isn't that cool?
No one knows.
Like, it's like...
This is my favorite spot.
This is...
This is your favorite spot?
Right here.
How come?
Uh, I don't know.
It's kind of hard to explain, I guess.
I'll try.
Uh, I don't know. It's kind of hard to explain, I guess.
Try.
Um...
Well, okay, like, that building, that's, uh...
That's been there since 1911.
And that, that's the Continental.
That's L.A.'s first skyscraper.
It was built in 1904.
What is that?
That?
That's a parking lot.
Oh.
Yeah, that's also a parking lot.
It's, um, yeah.
There's a lot of beautiful stuff here, too, though.
I don't know.
I just wish people would notice it more.
If it were me, if I'm, uh...
If it were you, what?
I don't know. I'd make them notice.
How would you make them notice?
I don't know. There's a lot of different stuff you could do.
Show me.
Please, I don't know anything about architecture.
You want me to draw you something?
Yeah.
I don't have any paper.
Well, use my arm.
Please, I need a tattoo.
Let's see what we can do.
That's the spirit.
Well, the buildings need to be integrated better, so we can maximize light capacity
here.
It's kind of messy.
That's okay.
For Tom Hanson, this was the night where everything changed.
That wall summer so often hid behind.
A wall of distance, of space, of casual.
That wall was slowly coming down.
For here was Tom, in her world.
A place few had been invited to see with their own eyes.
And here was Summer, wanting him there.
Him, no one else.
Have you ever been in a tornado?
No.
It's that and my teeth falling out.
I have that too.
You do?
Yeah. It's so weird. It's like being an old man.
What else do you have?
Earthquakes.
Really?
No.
No, I dream sometimes about flying.
It starts out like I'm running really, really fast.
I'm like superhuman.
And the terrain starts to get really rocky and steep.
And then I'm running so fast that my feet aren't even touching the ground.
And I'm floating.
And it's like this amazing, amazing feeling.
It's incredible.
I'm free. I'm safe.
Then I realize I'm completely alone.
And then I wake up.
As he listened, Tom began to realize that these weren't stories routinely told.
These were stories one had to earn.
He could feel the wall coming down.
He wondered if anyone else had made it this far.
Which is why the next six words changed everything.
I've never told anybody that before.
I guess I'm not just anybody.
So what are you exactly?
I don't know.
Are you her boyfriend?
It's not that simple.
Sure it is.
What, like, are we going steady?
Come on, guys, you know, we're adults.
We know how we feel.
We don't need to put labels on it.
I mean, boyfriend, girlfriend, all that stuff is...
It's really juvenile.
You sound gay.
You really do.
Okay, first of all,
your last girlfriend was Amy Sussman in the seventh grade,
and you dated for, like, three hours.
And you...
You've been with Robin since, what, like 1998?
97.
I don't think the two of you are exactly authorities
on modern relationships.
So what should I do?
You should ask her.
What?
Well, why rock the boat is what I'm thinking.
I mean, things are going well.
You start putting labels on it, that's
It's like the kiss of death. It's like saying, I love you.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
That's what happened between me and Sean.
What the hell's Sean?
My boyfriend before Mark.
Who the...
I'm lying. So, what you're saying...
I'm saying you do want to ask her.
It's obvious. You're just afraid he'll get Nancy you don't want,
which will shatter all the illusions about great these past few months have been.
And look, if it were me,
I find out now before we show up at her place and, well,
she's in bed with Lars from Norway.
Who's Lars from Norway?
Just some guy she met at the gym with.
Brad Pitt's face and Jesus' abs.
Wait, Coach, we're not done here.
Look, it's easy, Tom.
Just don't be a pussy.
You okay?
Yeah.
You sure?
Summer, I gotta ask you something.
What?
What are we, um...
What are we doing?
I thought we were going to the movies.
Yeah, no, I mean, like, what are we, like...
What's going on here with us?
I don't know.
Who cares?
I'm happy. Aren't you happy?
Yeah.
Good.
You still love me, is that possible?
Is that possible?
I hate this.
Some people like it.
I like how you dress.
I was thinking about getting a butterfly tattoo
about Ye Big on my ankle.
No.
Oh.
Yo.
How's it going?
Uh, okay.
You live around here?
Um, yeah, not too far.
Never seen you here before.
You're not too observant.
It's funny.
You're funny.
So let me buy you a drink.
No, thank you.
You with this guy?
Hey, I'm Tom. Whatever.
So come on, one drink. What are you drinking?
I said no thanks.
You're serious. This guy?
Hey, buddy. You know what? Don't be rude.
I'm flattered, but I'm not interested.
So why don't you go over there and leave us alone?
Thanks.
It's a free country.
Can't believe this is your boyfriend.
What are you doing?
It's really just a crazy thing.
It happened like...
It felt like it happened fast, but really...
It also felt like it was happening really slowly,
like everything all was just...
I don't know.
It doesn't feel like you'd think it would...
Hey.
What's the matter?
I just...
I can't believe you.
You can't believe me?
You were so completely, completely uncool in there.
Wait, wait, are you mad at me?
I just got my ass kicked for you.
Oh, really? Was that for me?
Was that for my benefit?
Yes, it was.
OK, well, next time, don't, because I
don't need your help.
You know what?
I'm really tired.
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
No.
You know what?
I'm not going anywhere until you tell me what's going on.
Nothing's going on.
We're just...
What?
We're just what?
We're just...
No, don't pull that with me.
Don't even try to...
This is not how you treat your friend.
Kissing in the copy room?
holding hands in Ikea, shower sex.
Come on, friends my balls.
I like you, Tom.
I just don't want to release you.
Well, you're not the only one that gets a say in this.
I do, too.
And I say we're a couple.
God damn it.
After you.
Please.
Come on.
I shouldn't have done that.
Done what?
Got mad at you.
I'm sorry.
Look, we don't have to put a label on it.
That's fine, I get it.
But, you know, I just...
I need some consistency.
You know, you're not gonna wake up in the morning
and feel differently.
I can't give you that.
Nobody can.
That hurt.
I'm sorry.
No, it doesn't hurt.
I like you.
All right.
You loved her, you were kissing.
Well, what about you?
Did you ever even have a boyfriend?
Of course.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Tell me about it.
Why not?
Because it's not important.
I'm interested.
All right, fine. You want to go there?
Yeah.
Fine.
I can take it.
So...
Well, in high school, there was Marcus.
Quarterback slash homecoming king.
No.
He was a rower.
He was very hot.
For a brief time in college, there was...
There was Charlie.
She was nice, but...
And then there was my semester in Siena.
Fernando Bellardelli.
Also known as the Puma.
The Puma?
Yeah, the Puma.
Because, you know...
So...
Oh, that's it?
The ones that last, yeah.
What happened? Why didn't they work out?
What always happens.
Life.
That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
No, it's not. It's awesome.
Trust me.
I'm serious.
I'll go first.
Penis.
There's kids around.
There are no kids around.
Penis.
You having fun?
Yeah.
It's the kind of thing you do with the puma, isn't it?
Oh, we've rarely left the room.
Penis!
Sorry, Tourette's.
You know how it is.
Penis!
She has it too.
I'm just looking over here.
I'm done. I'm done.
Are you done?
I'm done.
You're done?
Yeah.
This is too much.
Unleash me. I'm done.
Promise?
I promise.
Promise.
Penis!
It's very complex.
In a way it sort of like says so much by saying so little.
You want to go to the movies?
And that was his life now.
Every day the same pain of a wounded heart.
He is broken.
More than broken, he is alone.
Now, her only friend is the grudge.
Suffering.
So much suffering.
I'm sorry.
Tom, Mr. Vance would like to see you in his office.
Tom, have a seat.
Has something happened to you recently?
What do you mean?
Uh, death in the family, someone taken ill,
anything like that?
No.
Look, I don't mean to pry, but...
does this have something to do with Summer leaving?
Who?
My assistant.
Your, um...
Tom.
Everyone knows.
Never mind.
The reason I'm asking is, lately,
your work performance has been a little off.
I'm not following.
Okay, um, here's something that you wrote last week.
Roses are red, violets are blue.
Fuck you, whore.
Now, most shoppers at Valentine's Day...
Mr. Vance, are you firing me?
No. No.
Relax, Hanson.
You're one of the good ones.
Okay, uh, yeah, I'm sorry. Things have been a little difficult.
That's okay. I completely understand that.
I'm just saying that perhaps you could channel those energies, um, into something like this.
Funerals and sympathy.
Misery, sadness, loss of faith, no reason to live.
This is perfect for you.
Uh...
Good, okay.
Now back to work you go.
Thank you.
Hey.
Hey, don't you have like 20 cards to write by Friday?
Nope, all done.
Really? Can you help me?
Because I've run out of ways to say congrats.
Okay, I got good job, well done, and way to go.
That's it.
How about every day you make me proud,
but today you get a card.
Shit, that's good.
I know.
Have you tried Mary?
Mary!
We've been stuck on this for an hour.
How about...
I love us.
I hate Summer.
I hate her crooked teeth.
I hate her 1960s haircut.
I hate her knobby knees.
I hate her cockroach-shaped splotch on her neck.
I hate the way she smacks her lips before she talks.
I hate the way she sounds when she laughs.
I hate this song!
Son, you're gonna have to exit the vehicle.
I normally don't do blind dates,
but Paul and Robin spoke very highly of you.
They said you write greeting cards.
That's so interesting. I wanted to write.
I actually majored in English in college,
but what are you gonna do with that degree?
I went to Brown. Where did you go to...
Allison.
Hmm?
Listen, it's great to meet you, and...
you're a very attractive girl.
I just wanted to say up front that this isn't...
It's not gonna go anywhere.
Oh.
I liked this girl.
Yeah, I loved her. What'd she do?
She took a giant shit on my face.
Literally.
Literally?
Not literally.
That's disgusting.
Jesus.
What's the matter with you?
The point is, I messed up.
I am.
You know, on the one hand, I want to forget her.
On the other hand, I know that she's
the only person in the entire universe that will make me
happy.
You ever do this?
You think back on all the times you had with someone,
and you should replay it in your head over and over again.
and you look for those first signs of trouble.
There's two options, really.
Either she's an evil, emotionless, miserable human being,
or she's a robot.
A small wonder, you know, Vicki.
I'll explain a lot, actually.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah.
She never cheated on you?
No, never.
She'll take advantage of you in any way?
No.
And she told you up front that she didn't want a boyfriend?
Yeah.
I got a great idea.
That's the thing you can't explain away
My heart aches every day
Stand by me
Not at all.
That's it.
Go fight.
Go.
Let's volunteer.
Waste of time.
You don't look anything like yourself.
Hey, baby.
Hell no.
What do you mean, hell no?
I'm not going to that.
Yes, you are.
No, man, it's gonna be all old people.
Yeah, but you said you were going.
That's why I'm going.
And that's why I called her last night, told her I was sick.
Like a ninja.
I'm gonna... I'm not gonna know anybody at this thing.
Maybe you'll meet some hot granddaughters or something.
I'm hanging up, man.
Bye, baby.
Have your attention, please.
Passengers boarding the train in Los Angeles are waiting.
Passengers to get down are ready for delay.
Hi, Tom.
Hey, Summer.
I must have walked right by you.
Yeah.
Well, um, what are you doing?
Are you going to Millie's?
Me too.
Cool.
I forgot you knew her.
Yeah.
We work together all that time.
Of course.
I love Millie.
She's the sweetest.
She is.
How are you?
Good.
Good. I wrote to you. I never heard back.
Yeah, yeah, sorry about that.
I just, you know, it got kind of crazy.
The holidays came up, so work was...
You still working for Vance?
Yeah.
Well, I was going to go get a coffee if you want to...
Architecture of Happiness.
Yes.
That looks like a good book.
That's all.
Well, I don't want to bother you.
No, no, I, um...
Yeah, let's get coffee.
I have to.
Sweet disposition
And I'm too smooth
A moment of love, a dream, a lie
A kiss, a cry, our rights, our wrongs
You look nice.
Nice.
So you...
Well...
Penis.
No.
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Helping the kids out of their coats
The way the babies have been born
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh
Unpacking the bags and setting up
Planted lilacs and buttercups
Okay, what else you got?
Well, you snore.
No, I don't.
You do?
Yeah.
Well, you do too.
Oh, I definitely do.
And your feet reek.
That one time?
Every time.
That one time.
That one time especially, but every time.
And when you wake up, your hair sticks up like that.
It's ridiculous.
You're ridiculous.
Your favorite beetle is Ringo.
Damn right.
Ringo's the best.
Ringo is the s-
Oh!
He's fast!
Damn!
All right.
You got me.
Duck.
At last, my love has come along.
My lonely day is over.
And life is like a song.
Want to dance?
Yeah.
Very good.
Hey, I was wondering, um, I was gonna maybe have a party on Friday, um, on our rooftop
that has, like, a really nice garden.
Do you want to come?
Yeah.
If you're not busy.
I don't think I will be.
They're good, aren't they?
Very good.
I guess I just got lucky.
We met in elementary school.
In seventh grade, we had the same class schedule.
And we just clicked.
You know?
Love?
Shit, I don't know.
As long as she's cute and she's willing, right?
I'm flexible on the cute, so...
21 years.
She's the light that guides me home.
Yes, that is from one of our cards.
No, someone else wrote it.
Doesn't make it less true.
I think technically the girl of my dreams
would probably have, like, a really bodacious rack,
you know, maybe different hair.
You know, she'd probably be a little more into sports.
But, um, truthfully,
Robin's better than the girl of my dreams.
She's real.
Tom walked to her apartment,
intoxicated by the promise of the evening.
He believed that this time his expectations would align with reality.
Nice.
Your tie.
Hi.
How are you doing?
Good, how are you?
Good.
I, um...
That's so nice.
Thank you.
You shouldn't have.
That's so nice. Thank you so much.
No problem.
I'm excited to read it.
Yeah.
So Tom, what is it that you do?
I write greeting cards.
Tom could be a really great architect if he wanted to be.
That's unusual.
I mean, what made you go from one to the other?
I guess I just figured why make something
disposable like a building when you can make something
that lasts forever like a greeting card.
Oh my god.
What?
No, do you guys have a chance?
We're going to these meetings, but we're not doing any meeting.
And we're trying to be faithful, but we're cheating, cheating, cheating.
I'm the hero of the story, don't need to be saved.
It's all right.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
I never knew the cold had the danger
till I met this one and took it inside.
I can't get me out of the body like I was wrong.
Get a room.
Really.
I walked in the rain like a drone on the way to the moon.
Cheap and I know you're real
Shit.
I'm calling you every five minutes.
Are you okay?
I'm great.
What happened to you?
I don't want to talk about it.
You always want to talk about it.
About this.
Okay, well, come on, let's go.
Where are we going?
It's Thursday.
This one says, go for it.
And this one says, you can do it.
We have a whole line of inspirational photographic cards
featuring Pickles, my cat.
I think people will really enjoy them.
Thank you.
Good job, Rhoda.
That's inspirational stuff.
Okay.
Who's next?
We haven't heard from Sympathy in a while.
Hanson?
No.
The Winter Collection?
Do you have anything to contribute?
Uh, no.
I really don't.
Okay.
We'll come back to you.
Uh, Mackenzie?
Actually, you know what?
Yes, Tom?
Can I say something about the cat?
Well, okay.
Yeah, uh, this is...
And, Rhoda, no disrespect here,
but, um, this is total shit.
Tom, go for it and you can do it?
That's not inspirational. That's suicidal.
If Pickles goes for it right there, that's a dead cat.
This is lies. We're liars.
Think about it. Why do people buy these things?
It's not because they want to say how they feel.
People buy cards because they can't say how they feel
or they're afraid to.
We provide the service that lets them off the hook.
You know what? I say to hell with it.
Let's level with America.
At least let them speak for themselves, right?
I mean, look, what is this? What does this say?
Congratulations on your new baby, right?
How about congratulations on your new baby,
guess that's it for hanging out. Nice knowing you.
Sit down, Hanson.
How about this one with all the pretty hearts on the front?
I think I know where this is going.
Yeah! Happy Valentine's Day, sweetheart.
I love you. That's sweet.
Hey, love, Grant.
This is exactly what I'm talking about.
What does that even mean?
Love. Do you know?
Do you? Anybody?
Tom.
If somebody gave me this card, Mr. Vance, I would eat it.
It's these cards.
The movies and the pop songs, they're to blame for our lives.
and the heartache, everything.
And we're responsible.
I'm responsible.
I think we do a bad thing here.
People should be able to say how they feel,
how they really feel,
not, you know, some words that some strangers put in their mouths,
words like love.
That don't mean anything.
Sorry, I'm sorry.
I, uh...
I quit.
There's enough bullshit in the world without my help.
Hey, you're sketching again.
Yeah, well, just doodling.
Okay, Tom.
We got 20 seconds. Talk to me. You okay?
Yeah, I'm good. I'm great.
You know, my friends are all in love with you.
You know, it's like we said, plenty of other fish in the sea.
Thanks.
But, uh, those are guppies.
Yeah.
Hey, Tom?
Hmm?
Look, I know you think that she was the one.
But I don't.
No, I think you're just remembering the good stuff.
Next time you look back, I, uh...
I really think you should look again.
I love you.
It's playing at five.
Do you want to see it?
Um, I don't know.
We could just go back to your place or...
No, I really want to see it.
Let's go.
time it was and what a time it was it was
a time of innocence a time of confidence
is it the movie it's something i'm just i'm just being stupid
Yeah?
Yeah.
They're all that's left here.
It pains me we live in a world where nobody's heard of Spearmint.
I've never heard of them.
I put them on that mix I made you.
They're truck one.
Oh, yeah.
I'm sorry.
So, what do you want to do?
I think I'm just gonna call it a day.
You don't want to get some dinner?
Are you hungry?
You alright?
I'm just tired.
Okay.
I got it.
Pancakes.
I don't know.
I go out walking all day long
Take away this lonely mind
Soon it will be gone
Cause I'll tell you everything about
Living free
Yes, I can see you, God
Can you see me?
You don't need to know what I'm doing today.
It's as much as I know what you waste away.
Because I'll tell you everything about living free.
Yes, I can see you, girl.
Can you see me?
guitar solo
Because I'll tell you everything about being free
I'm sorry.
Hey, Tom.
I thought I might see you here.
I always loved this place ever since you brought me.
So I, uh...
I guess I should say congratulations.
Only if you mean it.
Ah, well, in that case...
So are you okay?
I will be.
Eventually.
Come on up.
I like your suit.
Ah, thanks.
You look sharp.
So do you.
Thanks.
I quit the office.
You did?
I didn't know. That's great.
You, um...
You're married.
Yeah. It's crazy, huh?
You should have told me.
I know.
When you were at the, you know, wedding and you were dancing.
Well, he hadn't asked me yet.
But he was in your life.
Yeah.
So why'd you dance with me?
Because I wanted to.
You just do what you want, don't you?
You never wanted to be anybody's girlfriend, and now you're somebody's wife.
It surprised me, too.
I don't think I'll ever understand that.
I mean, it doesn't make sense.
It just happened.
Right, but that's what I don't understand. What just happened?
I just... I just woke up one day and I knew.
Knew what?
What I was never sure of with you.
You know what sucks?
Realizing that everything you believe in is complete and utter bullshit sucks.
What do you mean?
You know, destiny and soul mates.
True love and all that childhood fairy tale nonsense.
You were right. I should have listened to you.
No.
Yeah, why are you smiling?
Oh.
What?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Well, you know, I guess it's because I was sitting in a deli and reading Dorian Gray
and a guy comes up to me and asks me about it and now he's my husband.
Yeah, so?
So what if I'd gone to the movies?
What if I had gone somewhere else for lunch?
What if I'd gotten there ten minutes later?
It was...
It was meant to be.
And I just kept thinking...
Tom was right.
No.
Yeah, I did.
I did.
It just wasn't me that you were right about.
I should go, but I'm really happy to see that you're doing well.
Summer.
I really do hope that you're happy.
The days of the year are unremarkable.
They begin and they end with no lasting memories made in between.
Most days have no impact on the course of a life.
May 23rd was a Wednesday.
Are you interviewing?
Sorry?
Are you interviewing for the position?
Oh, yeah. Why, are you?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm. My competition.
It would appear.
Yeah, so...
A little awkward.
Yeah.
Well, I hope you, um, don't get the job.
Well, I hope you don't get the job.
Have I seen you before?
Me? I don't think so.
Do you ever go to Angeles Plaza?
Yes. That's, like, my favorite spot in the city.
Okay, except for the parking lots, but...
Yeah, I agree.
Yeah, yeah, I think I've seen you there.
Really?
Yeah.
I haven't seen you.
You must not have been looking.
If Tom had learned anything, it was that you can't ascribe great cosmic significance to a simple earthly event.
Coincidence. That's all anything ever is.
Nothing more than coincidence.
Tom Hanson.
Yeah.
Come on back.
Thank you.
Tom had finally learned there are no miracles.
There's no such thing as fate.
Nothing is meant to be.
He knew.
He was sure of it now.
Tom was...
Sorry, um, I just left, uh...
Can I... One second.
He was pretty sure.
Hey.
You again.
Yeah, I, uh...
Just wondering if maybe after this,
if, um, you...
want to get some coffee or something.
Uh, I'm sorry.
I'm sort of supposed to meet someone after this.
Okay.
Sure.
What's up?
Why not?
Okay, well, then I'll just, uh,
I'll wait for you.
We'll figure it out.
My name's Tom.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Autumn.
She's got you high and you don't even know yet.
She's got you high and you don't even know yet
The sun's in the sky, it's warming up your bare legs
And you can't deny you're looking for the sunset
She's got you high and you don't even know yet
So search for the time before it leaves without you
Have you lost your mind or has she taken all of yours too?
What's this about? I figured love would shine through
We've lost romance, this world is turned so see-through
Open your mind, believe it's gonna come true
Romance alive, love, she's gonna tell you
What's this about? I figured love would shine through
We've lost romance, this world is turned so see-through
Open your mind, believe it's gonna come true
She wants a life, and she's gonna tell you
She's got you high, and you don't even know yet
The sun's in the sky, it makes for happy endings
You can't deny, you want the happy ending
She wants a life, and she's gonna tell you
We've lost romance, this world is time to see through
Open your mind, this love is gonna come through
Keep on and survive and hope, she's gonna tell you
She's got you high
What's this about?
I feel the love will shine through
We've lost our minds
This world is turned so see-through
Hold on your mind
Believe it's gonna come
You keep our minds alive
And hope she's gonna tell you
What's this about?
I feel the love will shine through
We've lost our minds
This world, this time so safe
Open your mind and believe
It's gonna come
To keep robots alive
And hope, she's gonna tell you
She's
Coming
High
© transcript Emily Beynon
Thank you.